<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-07-30T20:18:33+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Violet Evans</title><entry><title type="html">A Reflection on Practicum</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Reflection on Practicum" /><published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T20:17:32+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum.html"><![CDATA[<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>At the Institute, we all get assigned to practicum sponsors and teams of five for our yearlong project. Even though it was over 10 months ago, I still distinctly remember the nervous pit in my stomach when it was “reveal” day. With a class of 95 students and a split between Blue and Orange cohorts, I knew that I could end up with any four other classmates on my team. I also had no idea which government or corporate sponsor I’d be assigned to.</p>

<p>When reveal day came around, and as I tenderly opened the Google Sheets document revealing both sponsors and teammates simultaneously, I heaved out a sigh of relief. I got assigned to Andrew Burnette as team lead, who I knew to be level-headed, responsible, and kind. He and I were both in Blue cohort over the summer, and I had spoken to him a few times. I was unfamiliar with the other three names on the document- all three had been in Orange cohort over the summer and I had never spoken to them before. However, by graduation in May, our practicum team would be known as THE team; we all communicated well, produced incredible deliverables, and enjoyed each others’ company.</p>

<p>Tae Lee, my fellow Asian teammate, ended up being a close confidant throughout the job placement process. He and I did many mock interviews and prep together, and I always felt comfortable to talk with Tae whether it was about Asian cuisine, planning my solo trip to Korea, or asking about the D.C. food scene. Can you tell that I’m a foodie?</p>

<p>Blake Holmes, the class clown and lighthearted jokester, also became a great friend and helpful classmate. Since Blake and I often sat together in the front row, we often exchanged quips about our assignments. Never have I had a conversation with Blake and not felt immediately less stressed afterwards. Blake often helped lighten the mood of our team meetings with his seamless jokes.</p>

<p>I would say that my relationship with Salem Wear, the Alabama native and the only other girl on the team, had the most development. Initially, I expected us to automatically click and become close friends, especially since we were on the same homework team for the first fall module of the program. However, I experienced something like gradual friendship. As we continued through the fall semester and to the spring, I saw Salem to be responsible, kind, and conversational. One of her strengths throughout the job placement process was being able to empathize and remain positive. I also had the chance to partner with Salem on a practicum deliverable that focused on clustering. Through our working relationship, we became good friends and bonded over running.</p>

<p>Like all teams composed of diverse individuals, my team did have disagreements; however, one of our biggest strengths was communication. For example, if I had an idea that others disagreed about, I found that my teammates were willing to hear me through on my idea, make pro/con lists with me, and come to a team consensus on how to proceed. For example, I wanted our team to move over to Git for code changes and keeping consistency. I brought a PowerPoint deck to one of our meetings and suggested that we implement the strategy. Despite the difficulties in implementing the software on our remote servers, my team followed my PowerPoint instructions in getting Git set up. Once we completed the set up, various teammates voiced their concerns in a way that was both respectful but to the point. I appreciated the communication and willingness to give my idea a shot!</p>

<p>Reflecting on my time at the Institute, I feel that most of my challenges stemmed from the practicum project. Our team of five faced numerous obstacles and challenges in providing finalized deliverables to our sponsor. Despite this, I am incredibly grateful for my team’s support and flexibility. I hope to stay in touch!</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="teamwork," /><category term="ncsu," /><category term="practicum" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the Institute, we all get assigned to practicum sponsors and teams of five for our yearlong project. Even though it was over 10 months ago, I still distinctly remember the nervous pit in my stomach when it was “reveal” day. With a class of 95 students and a split between Blue and Orange cohorts, I knew that I could end up with any four other classmates on my team. I also had no idea which government or corporate sponsor I’d be assigned to.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/images/VEvans_Grad_20240418-38_Original.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/images/VEvans_Grad_20240418-38_Original.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Data Analytics?</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Data Analytics?" /><published>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T20:17:32+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column.html"><![CDATA[<p>During my first week in the program, the question I received the most was: “What made you want to come to the Institute?” Although my answer is complex, most often, I would respond that I studied biostatistics at UNC for my undergraduate studies – as if this was an explanation for pursuing graduate school. In this post, I reflect on my monumental experiences in undergrad by exploring my gradual realization of why I needed a master’s degree and discussing why I chose data analytics.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On Internship Experiences</p>

<p>Looking back at my three and a half years at UNC Chapel Hill, one of my proudest moments was when I received my dream summer internship at CVS Health. My main goal in professional extracurricular experiences was to gain real-world experience and get quality feedback on my work.</p>

<p>I saw CVS Health as an opportunity to get hands-on experience on projects under direct supervision while working on a team to achieve larger corporate goals. The internship provided me with just those dreams – I worked on a health equity roadmap intervention for dialysis patients in Austin, Texas, collaborated with communication team members to update the internal Sharepoint site, and even shadowed a master’s data science student working on a similar project about social determinants of health. 
The jobs right out of undergrad fit for my skill set seemed to be focused on statistical programming rather than having a larger variety of tasks and independence in projects, while graduate school would provide education on a specialist topic and help me gain in-depth knowledge. I found a year-long remote research position at the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS) and decided that this experience would cement my decision for the future – if I enjoyed research, I’d pursue a PhD; otherwise, I decided I would do a master’s.</p>

<p>My summer, fall, and spring at NIEHS was a huge learning curve, but it provided time where I could experiment in R Studio, better understand bioinformatics, and explore a federal research environment. My program guided eleven undergraduates in professional workshops and through poster presentations to a broader NIEHS audience. I found value in the networking opportunities and the collaborative teamwork elements of the program. I also realized I enjoyed the coding and problem-solving more than the aspects of genomic data and methodology.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On Graduate School</p>

<p>I recognized the necessity of obtaining a master’s degree, yet the recurring question that plagued me was, “Which specific field should I pursue?” Some criteria that cycled through my mind included being relatively affordable, with a strong preference for in-state in North Carolina, having less than a two-year commitment, and providing a strong record for employment following graduation. I debated between a degree in public health, business, or statistics; specifically, UNC has a great two-year biostatistics master of science, and Boston University has a one-year applied biostatistics program with good ties to the life sciences.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On the Institute</p>

<p>The gradual realization of why I needed graduate school began to outweigh all of my criteria for staying in the public health realm of my undergraduate major, and I began to learn about the Institute for Advanced Analytics and NCSU. The 10-month program fulfilled all of my criteria for graduate school, and an added benefit was the close proximity to my family. I began leaning towards the idea of a non-public health data science program and committed to my decision. Since I’ve been in the program, I haven’t looked back, not even once. The “why data analytics?” question quickly became answered as coursework in foundational statistics, Python and R programming, and summer practicum ramped up. I found myself immersed in how to communicate data science to a non-technical audience and set personal goals for applying data analytics. The application aspect of the program has been crucial to my development as a data scientist.</p>

<p>In the last three months, I’ve already assembled a complete pie of knowledge and skills. Each slice on my plate represents a different aspect of our cohort’s learning journey, including statistics, programming, ethical considerations for data professionals, cross-cultural communication, computer security, networking in a professional context, and the art of setting tangible goals. We continue to fill our plates, one day at a time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="graduate school" /><category term="NCSU" /><category term="Institute for Advanced Analytics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During my first week in the program, the question I received the most was: “What made you want to come to the Institute?” Although my answer is complex, most often, I would respond that I studied biostatistics at UNC for my undergraduate studies – as if this was an explanation for pursuing graduate school. In this post, I reflect on my monumental experiences in undergrad by exploring my gradual realization of why I needed a master’s degree and discussing why I chose data analytics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 2</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/15/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 2" /><published>2019-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T20:17:32+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/15/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/15/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I’ve returned home, life’s kept me moving. I came back to an untouched bedroom, an ever-busy and hectic schedule with my dad, a similar lifestyle at my mom’s, and the same high school friends doing the same exact things around town. However, over the last few days, I’ve felt like I need to recapture my experience abroad: to reflect, to think, and to improve from my experiences. So my first real blog post here is about my Month 1: September.</p>

<p>The first month really felt like a blur. There was, of course, an adjustment period: to the strange foreigners-living-abroad culture, my new Italian roommate, and living by myself for the first time ever. I needed to learn how to walk around my new campus at Nanjing Normal University without getting lost, where to get food, and how to  cope with only having myself as a reliable source of help. It was hard to eat dinner alone, to look on social media, and feel lonely while my friends from home had already settled into their college lifestyles.</p>

<p>Yet, I grew by myself. I realized a lot about home, both good and bad. I came to understand that high school was a bubble: nobody in the big picture cares about what you wear, where you live, or how many connections to school programs you have past those four years. Honestly, I’ve only kept a few strong relationships this past year from all people I spent four years with; mostly, I have memories. In the meantime, I began meeting other foreigners around campus and during touristy outings arranged in our group chat. Some were also on the same scholarship as I, others were friends with my roommate. An important person in my first month was another student on a gap year from a similar region as I in North Carolina (the Triangle); we were able to connect because of similar backgrounds and the same feeling of being lost. I also began forming a special relationship with my roommate that would be unparalleled with anyone else throughout the rest of the year.</p>

<p>As I made it through registration, venturing to the canteen without walking the opposite direction, and prepping for the placement exam in the school library, classes soon started. I began taking full immersion Chinese classes from 8 to 11:50 in the morning, with mostly Italians in my class that had come with my roommate from the same university in Italy. My classes felt strange: not because they were taught in a different language, but because there was hardly any REAL homework and the amount of effort I had to put in was significantly less than high school.</p>

<p>I soon got in a schedule, though, and I felt content. I knew the people in my class, I began friendships with other scholarship students, and my roommate and I ventured around the giant city taking the subway to shop, dine, or visit Nanjing landmarks. Life was good, life was settling.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since I’ve returned home, life’s kept me moving. I came back to an untouched bedroom, an ever-busy and hectic schedule with my dad, a similar lifestyle at my mom’s, and the same high school friends doing the same exact things around town. However, over the last few days, I’ve felt like I need to recapture my experience abroad: to reflect, to think, and to improve from my experiences. So my first real blog post here is about my Month 1: September.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 1</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/06/10/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 1" /><published>2019-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T20:17:32+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/06/10/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/06/10/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m sitting on a bench. Crying. Not because my legs are full of mosquito bites, not because I have to wait for my friend to finish her project and meet me, and not because I’m sweaty from hiking.</p>

<p>I’m sitting on a bench, crying, because I’ve realized how far I’ve come. After being abroad in Nanjing, China for ten months, I’ve gotten to meet up with one of my closest friends in high school. I was able to meet her other American classmates, talk to her roommate, and share my last year of experiences here in China.</p>

<p>And I’m not sad I’m leaving in a month. I’m ready to go home. Instead, I’m crying because of the growth I’ve experienced. I’ve come so far from being a seventeen year-old, ready to take on the world for a gap year before college. I’ve overcome so many obstacles, made crazy friendships, and learned incredible things about this world. All of these statements seem so broad, yet they’re all true. I’ve grown, and I’m proud of it.</p>

<p>So as I’m sitting on this bench, clicking through photos of friends from home, voice messaging friends back in Nanjing, and calling my mom, I’ve decided to start a blog. A blog chronicling the main difficulties I’ve experienced, the amazingness of studying abroad, and how much it means to be grounded, present- what it’s like to live in the moment, accept your surroundings, and grow.</p>

<p>Stay tuned, readers.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m sitting on a bench. Crying. Not because my legs are full of mosquito bites, not because I have to wait for my friend to finish her project and meet me, and not because I’m sweaty from hiking.]]></summary></entry></feed>