<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-07-30T21:03:03+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Violet Evans</title><entry><title type="html">A Reflection on Practicum</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Reflection on Practicum" /><published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum.html"><![CDATA[<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>At the Institute, we all get assigned to practicum sponsors and teams of five for our yearlong project. Even though it was over 10 months ago, I still distinctly remember the nervous pit in my stomach when it was “reveal” day. With a class of 95 students and a split between Blue and Orange cohorts, I knew that I could end up with any four other classmates on my team. I also had no idea which government or corporate sponsor I’d be assigned to.</p>

<p>When reveal day came around, and as I tenderly opened the Google Sheets document revealing both sponsors and teammates simultaneously, I heaved out a sigh of relief. I got assigned to Andrew Burnette as team lead, who I knew to be level-headed, responsible, and kind. He and I were both in Blue cohort over the summer, and I had spoken to him a few times. I was unfamiliar with the other three names on the document- all three had been in Orange cohort over the summer and I had never spoken to them before. However, by graduation in May, our practicum team would be known as THE team; we all communicated well, produced incredible deliverables, and enjoyed each others’ company.</p>

<p>Tae Lee, my fellow Asian teammate, ended up being a close confidant throughout the job placement process. He and I did many mock interviews and prep together, and I always felt comfortable to talk with Tae whether it was about Asian cuisine, planning my solo trip to Korea, or asking about the D.C. food scene. Can you tell that I’m a foodie?</p>

<p>Blake Holmes, the class clown and lighthearted jokester, also became a great friend and helpful classmate. Since Blake and I often sat together in the front row, we often exchanged quips about our assignments. Never have I had a conversation with Blake and not felt immediately less stressed afterwards. Blake often helped lighten the mood of our team meetings with his seamless jokes.</p>

<p>I would say that my relationship with Salem Wear, the Alabama native and the only other girl on the team, had the most development. Initially, I expected us to automatically click and become close friends, especially since we were on the same homework team for the first fall module of the program. However, I experienced something like gradual friendship. As we continued through the fall semester and to the spring, I saw Salem to be responsible, kind, and conversational. One of her strengths throughout the job placement process was being able to empathize and remain positive. I also had the chance to partner with Salem on a practicum deliverable that focused on clustering. Through our working relationship, we became good friends and bonded over running.</p>

<p>Like all teams composed of diverse individuals, my team did have disagreements; however, one of our biggest strengths was communication. For example, if I had an idea that others disagreed about, I found that my teammates were willing to hear me through on my idea, make pro/con lists with me, and come to a team consensus on how to proceed. For example, I wanted our team to move over to Git for code changes and keeping consistency. I brought a PowerPoint deck to one of our meetings and suggested that we implement the strategy. Despite the difficulties in implementing the software on our remote servers, my team followed my PowerPoint instructions in getting Git set up. Once we completed the set up, various teammates voiced their concerns in a way that was both respectful but to the point. I appreciated the communication and willingness to give my idea a shot!</p>

<p>Reflecting on my time at the Institute, I feel that most of my challenges stemmed from the practicum project. Our team of five faced numerous obstacles and challenges in providing finalized deliverables to our sponsor. Despite this, I am incredibly grateful for my team’s support and flexibility. I hope to stay in touch!</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="teamwork," /><category term="ncsu," /><category term="practicum" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the Institute, we all get assigned to practicum sponsors and teams of five for our yearlong project. Even though it was over 10 months ago, I still distinctly remember the nervous pit in my stomach when it was “reveal” day. With a class of 95 students and a split between Blue and Orange cohorts, I knew that I could end up with any four other classmates on my team. I also had no idea which government or corporate sponsor I’d be assigned to.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/images/VEvans_Grad_20240418-38_Original.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/images/VEvans_Grad_20240418-38_Original.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Data Analytics?</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Data Analytics?" /><published>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column.html"><![CDATA[<p>During my first week in the program, the question I received the most was: “What made you want to come to the Institute?” Although my answer is complex, most often, I would respond that I studied biostatistics at UNC for my undergraduate studies – as if this was an explanation for pursuing graduate school. In this post, I reflect on my monumental experiences in undergrad by exploring my gradual realization of why I needed a master’s degree and discussing why I chose data analytics.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On Internship Experiences</p>

<p>Looking back at my three and a half years at UNC Chapel Hill, one of my proudest moments was when I received my dream summer internship at CVS Health. My main goal in professional extracurricular experiences was to gain real-world experience and get quality feedback on my work.</p>

<p>I saw CVS Health as an opportunity to get hands-on experience on projects under direct supervision while working on a team to achieve larger corporate goals. The internship provided me with just those dreams – I worked on a health equity roadmap intervention for dialysis patients in Austin, Texas, collaborated with communication team members to update the internal Sharepoint site, and even shadowed a master’s data science student working on a similar project about social determinants of health. 
The jobs right out of undergrad fit for my skill set seemed to be focused on statistical programming rather than having a larger variety of tasks and independence in projects, while graduate school would provide education on a specialist topic and help me gain in-depth knowledge. I found a year-long remote research position at the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS) and decided that this experience would cement my decision for the future – if I enjoyed research, I’d pursue a PhD; otherwise, I decided I would do a master’s.</p>

<p>My summer, fall, and spring at NIEHS was a huge learning curve, but it provided time where I could experiment in R Studio, better understand bioinformatics, and explore a federal research environment. My program guided eleven undergraduates in professional workshops and through poster presentations to a broader NIEHS audience. I found value in the networking opportunities and the collaborative teamwork elements of the program. I also realized I enjoyed the coding and problem-solving more than the aspects of genomic data and methodology.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On Graduate School</p>

<p>I recognized the necessity of obtaining a master’s degree, yet the recurring question that plagued me was, “Which specific field should I pursue?” Some criteria that cycled through my mind included being relatively affordable, with a strong preference for in-state in North Carolina, having less than a two-year commitment, and providing a strong record for employment following graduation. I debated between a degree in public health, business, or statistics; specifically, UNC has a great two-year biostatistics master of science, and Boston University has a one-year applied biostatistics program with good ties to the life sciences.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On the Institute</p>

<p>The gradual realization of why I needed graduate school began to outweigh all of my criteria for staying in the public health realm of my undergraduate major, and I began to learn about the Institute for Advanced Analytics and NCSU. The 10-month program fulfilled all of my criteria for graduate school, and an added benefit was the close proximity to my family. I began leaning towards the idea of a non-public health data science program and committed to my decision. Since I’ve been in the program, I haven’t looked back, not even once. The “why data analytics?” question quickly became answered as coursework in foundational statistics, Python and R programming, and summer practicum ramped up. I found myself immersed in how to communicate data science to a non-technical audience and set personal goals for applying data analytics. The application aspect of the program has been crucial to my development as a data scientist.</p>

<p>In the last three months, I’ve already assembled a complete pie of knowledge and skills. Each slice on my plate represents a different aspect of our cohort’s learning journey, including statistics, programming, ethical considerations for data professionals, cross-cultural communication, computer security, networking in a professional context, and the art of setting tangible goals. We continue to fill our plates, one day at a time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="graduate school" /><category term="NCSU" /><category term="Institute for Advanced Analytics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During my first week in the program, the question I received the most was: “What made you want to come to the Institute?” Although my answer is complex, most often, I would respond that I studied biostatistics at UNC for my undergraduate studies – as if this was an explanation for pursuing graduate school. In this post, I reflect on my monumental experiences in undergrad by exploring my gradual realization of why I needed a master’s degree and discussing why I chose data analytics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 8</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/22/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 8" /><published>2019-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/22/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/22/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>After taking a four month pause from my blog to concentrate on my first semester of college, I’ve realized I need to finish recounting this journey. So much in China occurred that has shaped my life back in the US. I can’t even begin to explain the amount of influence this gap year has had on my mindset, on my interactions with other people, and the mentality that I can now take with me in my everyday activities. Reflecting on my school life at UNC, I’ve come to understand that I need to wrap this blog up for me, for closure.</p>

<p>Reading back over my March journal entries and revisiting the hoards of pictures taken has made me realize how much my second semester in China changed me. I think that this month was the start of a type of carefree freedom, an ability to drop all responsibilities and travel, to go explore, to go meet new people. I wanted to learn more about myself and see more new things.</p>

<p>March seems like light years away, something that happened in the past and shaped me, and feels so far off in the distance it’s almost intangible. So much occurred, from the start of a new semester to fresh social dynamics, it’s important to explain.</p>

<p>The beginning of the month was refreshing. Not only did I get a new roommate and had so much fun helping her around the city, from Walmart shopping adventures (free samples, anyone??) and showing her my favorite food spots, I also got to meet up with old friends. It was so fun to go back to school and actually have friends to text and meet up with. I reconnected with people over gifts and laughter and good food to share our holiday break’s stories; it was busy, but absolutely so full of happiness.</p>

<p>Something weird about March was the new social dynamic, because after the Italians from first semester left, there was a group of about 20 people from our old friend group staying. We all knew each other fairly well, but I think everyone began feeling like they needed their own space. This Westerner group was coined “The Survivors”, and our group chat became a place for random jokes and laughs, but actual tight-knit group dinners really died out.</p>

<p>As our first semester friend group became looser, I began exploring new friendships. I felt socially stretched, where I had my good friends Iana and Josi, and a few others I could comfortably talk to, but I also had my new Korean roommate, JiSoo. Having a Korean friend made a whole new realm of Asian friends open up at school. As the new semester began, I started going with Jisoo and her two friends to lunch. Although there were some Japanese and Korean students taking classes the first semester at NNU, I never really had the opportunity to interact with them. The new semester’s lunch allowed me to meet so many new people and use my Chinese more!</p>

<p>An important point about my old friends was that they really encouraged me to spend time with Jisoo. I was sad that I wouldn’t be able to see them as often, but I really did want to meet new people outside The Survivors group. I was thankful that my old friends wanted me to grow out of my comfort zone just as much as I did, and accepted me for who I was. I introduced my roommate to all my old friends at a birthday party, but the dynamic felt too foreign and uncomfortable for both of us. It was ok though, and I was more than glad to go with my new roommate to lunch and meet new people! Balancing school, old friends, and new friends was a real challenge, but I really loved my new adventures.</p>

<p>Another great part of the new semester was moving up to 三年级二班. My class was half full of Thai students, all from the same Thai university, and the other half of the class was just individual high-level students that were from various countries. I really enjoyed the harder content of my new classes and the fresh faces. Also, I began speaking to people in class only in Chinese, and I really enjoyed that I had a new group of people to converse with.</p>

<p>Other than the new social dynamics, I’d say that if I could highlight three great things of the new semester they would be:
1) Beginning visiting a fancy yoga studio with a free membership card my friend Matteo gave me
2) Joining taekwondo practice in Xianlin, the other NNU campus, more actively
3) Taking lots of food pictures</p>

<p>I guess I’ve always liked taking photos of things, because I remember religiously holding a mini Canon camera beginning in third grade on summer trips around China. In March, I really started taking LOADS of food pictures; I mean my camera roll was filled with pretty foods, strange foods, people with food, and any other situation food could possibly be in. My friends from home even started commenting when I sent them entire albums of not my adventures around Nanjing, but my food.</p>

<p>Lastly, one of the most memorable events of the month was a last minute backpacking trip to Wuyuan County, in Jiangxi Province. My American friend Mackenzie invited me for a weekend adventure backpacking around the county to see some of the famous seasonal 油菜花 (canola flowers). Although it was only a four day adventure, so much occurred; we hit up five different villages, had an adventure with our 缘分车, and missed our train on the way there (what a way to start out the weekend). If you want to hear about our stories of re-booking tickets, finding last minute places to stay the night of, and trying various 年糕 (sticky rice patties), ask me about it! Way too much happened in the span of this adventure to recount in this blog. Let me say, this adventure was surely a great way to wrap up the month.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After taking a four month pause from my blog to concentrate on my first semester of college, I’ve realized I need to finish recounting this journey. So much in China occurred that has shaped my life back in the US. I can’t even begin to explain the amount of influence this gap year has had on my mindset, on my interactions with other people, and the mentality that I can now take with me in my everyday activities. Reflecting on my school life at UNC, I’ve come to understand that I need to wrap this blog up for me, for closure.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 7</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/17/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 7" /><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/17/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/17/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>A Dedication to My Cat, Tootsie Roll</p>

<p>Change is real, and change is happening. Every single minute of the day, something on this planet changes. Whether it’s an event that resonates with us for every moment of our lives following it, or a minuscule change in another person’s life across the globe, it occurs. And it’s real.</p>

<p>Something I admit I have yet to embrace is change. My transition from a small, private middle school to high school was hard, and the transition from a North Carolina public high school, with 2,400 students in it, to my gap year in Nanjing was not easy either. So as move in day at my in-state, American university approaches, I feel hesitant to express my feelings.</p>

<p>February, my half-way mark of being abroad in China, really embodied these thoughts– change was in the winds, and I wasn’t sure how to feel about it. My month began with another trip to Guilin, Guangxi Province. I had been twice already that year, for both a holiday break in October, and in January with some friends, but I wanted to spend Chinese New Year (also known as the Spring Festival) with some family there. So, again, I hopped on a plane and traveled back to my birthplace.</p>

<p>During the eight or nine days of Spring Festival that I was there, I had the opportunity to meet lots of Guangxi Province locals that stopped in to pay a visit to my foster parents. I was staying with my foster parents and their daughter, so as tradition is pretty strictly still followed, almost all of their extended family members that lived fairly near came to 拜访 (visit and pay their respects). In summary, we ate so much delicious food, I had lots of people tell me their last memories of me as a baby, and then I fell really sick.</p>

<p>While my foster sister, her husband and I were in his old hometown in southern, rural  Guangxi Province, I started throwing up. I didn’t know why I was so sick; the only reason I could think of was that eating this delicacy that was a fried mix of sandworms with cashews made me sick. I think I also had a pretty high fever because I felt really light-headed and could hardly walk. The photo below is of the house where we stayed.</p>

<p>Upon return to Nanjing, I still didn’t really recover. I was staying at my mom’s house, about an hour from my campus, so I had all my meals provided for and didn’t have to worry about laundry (shout out to Mom, thanks!). However, I slept a lot and still continued having a lot of stomach problems. I did do a couple of things around the house, though. Below is a photo of me making 汤圆 (tāng yuán), a sticky rice dessert eaten for the Lantern Festival, which lands on the 15th day of the Spring festival; it marks the end of the holiday.</p>

<p>During this month of my holiday break, I also celebrated my 18th birthday. It was strange being away from my dad, my cats, my dog, and my friends, but I had my mom, so that was great! Here’s a picture of me and my cake.</p>

<p>Something that I experienced that was especially hard were changes back home in North Carolina. My beloved cat, Tootsie Roll, passed away at the old age of 13. My dad had gone to pet her and apparently she was cold. I felt such sadness and knew I had lost my life-long best friend when the news was broken to me, because through every stage of my life, my cat had been there for me. Well, cats can only be there so much for a human, but Tootsie was always lounging around looking for a pet, so if I ever needed an instant pillow, she was an easy first option. Tootsie also was always my warm blanket at night, my fluffy buddy, and my least favorite morning alarm. Being away from home for so long, already experiencing my family cat Tuffy’s death, and then changes in my dad’s life, my kitty cat’s death really was a wake-up call that change is inevitable. It’s always happening, it affects us all, and there’s nothing we can do to stop it.</p>

<p>So my month ended with lots of changes. Not actually a lot happened in Nanjing, because I wasn’t in school, but I found out three things: I caught a bacterial intestinal infection, I began feeling very old after becoming ‘legal’, and things at home in the US were changing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Dedication to My Cat, Tootsie Roll]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 6</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/07/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 6" /><published>2019-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/07/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/07/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>January was a really, really good month and every one of my days, for the most part, were different.</p>

<p>Beginning with my week one, I began wrapping up my holiday feelings. No more festivities past our New Year’s Eve party, no more group dinners, and no more free time with friends. Well, I did go to a big dinner the night before a final exam, but that was an exception– we went to get the famous Beijing roast duck! The first week, I had to begin studying for my four classes of Chinese. Two classes were main “core” class, Chinese reading/writing and a listening/speaking class; the other two were for essay writing and composition and business Chinese.</p>

<p>I really felt confused studying for exams during the second week: not because I did not understand the content, but because I wasn’t quite sure what I was studying for. My grades did not transfer back to college in the US, and I never had planned to study anything Chinese related in college. My motivation definitely lacked during this week, but I crammed all the content in and finished with all A’s for the semester.</p>

<p>The third and fourth week of January were some of the best weeks I experienced in China. My friends and I had planned a big trip to Guilin, Guangxi for sightseeing around the city and visiting the nearby rice terraces after exams finished. Guilin happens to be my hometown and birthplace, so although I did hesitate at first about joining, but once I made my decision to tag along, I was exuberated! We took an 8-hour train ride down to Guilin, stayed in an amazing hostel, explored the city (with me as everyone’s guide, of course), and tried some yummy foods.</p>

<p>As wonderful as the week was, traveling with seven other people can be very exhausting. Some of my best friends, the Italians, were not returning the following semester, so I said my tearful goodbyes and wished them good luck, then flew back to Nanjing. I only had a couple days back in Nanjing before my family and I vacationed in Thailand for a week, so I settled in at my mom’s and focused on packing.</p>

<p>Switching from traveling with seven other young people, down to do anything and visit everything, to traveling with a four year old (my sister) was quite a transition. My mom, stepdad, sister and I spent a whole week in Bangkok, and our time there was very slow and relaxing. All the Thai food we tried, from nice and air-conditioned restaurants to aromatic street food, blew my mind. Also, the famous landmarks were amazing to sightsee and easy to get to, all with a venture on the SkyTrain and boat ride down the Chao Phraya River. Pictured below are some of my favorite sights, foods, and things we did.</p>

<p>I wrapped up my contrasting month with a big change– I cut off 8 inches of my hair! Before leaving the US, I planned that I would cut off as much hair as possible to donate to non-profit hair donation center. However, my hair grew really long over the first semester, almost hitting my elbow, and I could not stand it any longer. I got a salon recommendation from my Chinese friend, booked an appointment online, and headed over for the big chop with my friend Emily. The hairdresser almost cut off the eight inches without the hair being tied in the ponytail, which would’ve been tragic, but Emily caught his mistake, and I walked out of the salon with eight less inches of hair on my head. The haircut symbolized a new start, a fresh look, and a willingness to make the rest of my year as good as the last few weeks.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[January was a really, really good month and every one of my days, for the most part, were different.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 5</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/01/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 5" /><published>2019-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/01/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/01/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>As I return to the inside my grandparent’s lake house in Michigan from a nice summer boat ride, I began to think, how can so much beauty be in such familiar things? Actually, my first thought was the common saying, “beauty is in the simple things”. However, if I think back to December, I know that beauty is not always in the SIMPLE things, because simple things can be foreign, too…</p>

<p>Thinking about my first three months, December was comparably a much better month. Although during the beginning of the month I struggled with the decision of whether or not to go with my friend group to Xi’An on a vacation, I was able to set a regular routine and became very happy with the people I had formed relationships with.</p>

<p>One of the main events of December for me was running a 3k during the weekend that my friends went out of town. My Russian friend, Iana, and I headed over to Xianlin for a provincial wide “marathon”. There were several distances and courses spread out around the university campus, but we didn’t have a running team, so unfortunately we were not able to run a marathon or even a half marathon. So we bundled up in below freezing weather, drank lots of hot water, and ran our 3k. The organization skills of the event were not that great, but this event set the precedent for heading to the gym more and putting exercise back into my daily routine.</p>

<p>So after classes and between group dinners, I began heading to the gym with my American friend Mackenzie. Oftentimes, the outside temperature would be in the 30’s, and more times than not the pollution levels were hazardous. Running outside was simply not even an option, and biking (outside) to Nanjing University, another university located near us to access their gym was not a very good choice, either. Because I ran track and cross country off and on throughout high school, I really missed exercising. And although I did have to walk everywhere in China, I sometimes really craved a good workout. Therefore, the gym, although not connected to our university, was the best option. I always felt better after a treadmill session!</p>

<p>Also during December, I began spending a lot more time with my language exchange group. The Russian friend mentioned above, Iana, had organized this group back in September, and we met weekly to have dinner, do fun activities around Nanjing, and communicate in both English and Chinese. The group included two Chinese girls that were English majors, Iana, my friend Alex from the same area of North Carolina as I, and myself. The five us began rehearsing for a New Year’s rehearsal and spent three to four times a week practicing. Although it was quite time consuming, I was really happy with the opportunity to get to see my new friends more often. Photographed below are both the performance itself and one of the dinners we had together.</p>

<p>One of the highlights of this month was Christmas. Although not all of us were Christian, we were all foreigners away from home, mostly from countries that celebrate Christmas. It was quite strange to be in a place where there were not stores full of commercial products, jolly songs floating around, and a tree to put presents underneath. Before I left, of course I knew that America as a whole is a very Christian country, but I could only keep that in mind, not knowing that it would feel empty without a general Christmas mood in the air.</p>

<p>Therefore, we all took matters into our hands. My American neighbor, Will organized a Secret Santa exchange for gifts. I set up a SignUpGenius for a Christmas Eve dinner, and the two of us worked together with my roommate Giulia to categorize foods for people to bring. After much planning, we did successfully pull it off. At the party, there were so many different ethnic foods; it included things from German potato salad and Polish pierogi to Thai salad and Chinese fried rice, and of course, I brought my homemade peanut butter jelly sandwiches.</p>

<p>Overall, December was a very busy month. I was hardly ever in my room, and between classes, eating lunch with my friends, rehearsals/ language exchange meetings, and the gym, I began attending a taekwondo club in Xianlin with Iana. Although I never completely gave up on making Chinese friends through clubs, I did realize my expectations would not be lived up to. But I was content, looking forward to exams in mid-January, and becoming even better friends with people I had known in previous months.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I return to the inside my grandparent’s lake house in Michigan from a nice summer boat ride, I began to think, how can so much beauty be in such familiar things? Actually, my first thought was the common saying, “beauty is in the simple things”. However, if I think back to December, I know that beauty is not always in the SIMPLE things, because simple things can be foreign, too…]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 4</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/27/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 4" /><published>2019-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/27/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/27/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>November in the United States is a special month; it is a month of being thankful, rejoicing with family, and being glad you survived almost another year. For me, however, November was one of the hardest months being abroad. Perhaps it was the hazardous pollution that reached into the 200’s (where anything above 100 is technically unsafe), or maybe it was still a matter of an adaptation period. After all, it is only Americans that celebrate Thanksgiving, so being around non-Americans celebrating different holidays abroad was quite weird at first.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I experienced my first bout of homesickness in November. As midterms were to be held in the beginning of November, I began studying pretty hard. I wanted to make sure my grades were good because although they didn’t transfer to my university in the US for the following year, they were the purpose of my study period in China and the pure validity for many people that my time abroad was worthy. Maybe others did not know that this year would be about finding my identity, my beliefs, and my comforts, but these grades sure were important.</p>

<p>Also, it didn’t help that I got sick during midterm week. Surely, it was not anything more than a minor cold, but it sent me into a mentality of missing EVERYTHING. I missed my cats, my dad, my friends from high school, driving a car, all the cheesy comfort foods, and almost anything that comes to mind with the American lifestyle. I just wanted my old lifestyle back, with another clear sense of purpose I felt in high school, which was to maintain good grades to get into a prestigious university. My year abroad did not actually have a main goal other than improving my Chinese, and I struggled with those goals all of the first semester.</p>

<p>So while I missed home and began actually reaching out to friends and family from home, my friends at Nanjing Normal became even closer. I formed a friend group with my roommate Giulia, the previously mentioned half-German, half-Chinese girl named Emily, and another German girl Josi. We all ate dinner every night together, and although it was a good time, we did eat a lot later than I was used to. It took some adjustment to have to comply with other people’s wants and needs, and although it may have resulted in some unhealthy choices, I did need that situation of being made uncomfortable and the change from the expectation of usual instant gratification to make myself more able to accept change.</p>

<p>Of course during the duration of this month, other than academics and a social life, I did keep busy with activities. I attended a fun track meet in Xianlin, went to Yangzhou (another city in JiangSu Province located near Nanjing) with a big group of friends, and visited touristy sites throughout the city. In the photo collage below are pictures of all the mentioned events I participated in. I also bought my heavy winter jacket in preparation for the freezing, polluted Nanjing and brought my roommate to my mom’s about an hour from Nanjing Normal University for a Thanksgiving dinner.</p>

<p>Overall, November was a weird month. I became content with the good friends I had made, completely immersed in the foreigner culture at school, and happy with my regular schedule (except dinner was too late). I did also enjoy my adventures around in Nanjing and first experience on a Chinese train in five years when we headed to Yangzhou. Yet, I still was searching for my ultimate purpose abroad and the true calling.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[November in the United States is a special month; it is a month of being thankful, rejoicing with family, and being glad you survived almost another year. For me, however, November was one of the hardest months being abroad. Perhaps it was the hazardous pollution that reached into the 200’s (where anything above 100 is technically unsafe), or maybe it was still a matter of an adaptation period. After all, it is only Americans that celebrate Thanksgiving, so being around non-Americans celebrating different holidays abroad was quite weird at first.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 3</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/24/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 3" /><published>2019-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/24/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/24/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>Looking back to October, I’d have to say my second month abroad included a whole lot of mixed feelings. Unfortunately, when we go abroad, we not only pack up our suitcases, memories, and belongings, but we also bring our expectations with us.</p>

<p>My first month in China was really, really good. It was about settling, beginning new friendships, and leaving old grievances behind. However, when I hit the second month, especially after our one week break during the state holiday week of October called “The Golden Week”, I came to realize I was unhappy in some aspects. But I’ll get to that only after I describe my holiday.</p>

<p>If you all, as readers, had one week with no classes, no obligations, and no idea what in the world to do to kill time (and were living abroad), what would be the best option? Traveling, of course. Due to the fact that I have connections in Guilin, China, I headed out of Nanjing as soon as classes ended for the one week holiday. I hadn’t been back in five years since I had visited every summer when I was little with my mom. So all I brought with me were memories, plans of eating 桂林米粉 (THE famous Guilin rice noodles), and an idea of what my visit was going to be like.</p>

<p>During my trip, I had the opportunity to visit family, take a trip to the countryside, and do lots of local things– such as eating, shopping, and cooking. Nothing actually significant happened, but I did have one big epiphany- the way I grew up in the US was a whole lot different than the people I met in Guilin did. Perhaps when I was little I didn’t have a good gauge on social situations, customs, or what local norms were. But now, I do, and I felt a taste of the privilege of the way I was raised. People shared their stories with me: from working on railways to support their families to discussing governmental pay; my foster mom even shared that she had to help raise her own siblings in the 苦 (bitterness and bearing of hardships) of the Cultural Revolution.</p>

<p>Therefore, going back to Nanjing, I had a lot going on in my mind. I had the opportunity to see the real China for the first time as an adult, and had sensed the deepness of the Chinese spirit to persevere. Before I departed on the Golden Week break, I had made plans to join clubs in Nanjing Normal University’s other campus, Xianlin, where all the bachelor students are located. My own campus, located in the heart of downtown, is only for master’s students; our campus is literally dead, with no fun campus events to be found, ever. So I returned to the student life in Nanjing and my previous plans on forming good, deep relationships with some Chinese people and learning more about the culture where I was born.</p>

<p>So I began commuting to a few school clubs in Xianlin I had committed to because they seemed interesting and exciting. One in particular was an English club. I thought that if I could find some open-minded Chinese people that wanted to learn about my background, my past, and my American culture, we could be friends. I was wrong. My plans on joining that club backfired– I was ignored, excluded from conversation topics, and considered an outsider. Maybe it’s the way I look, because I am Chinese-American, that Chinese students didn’t find anything special to talk about with me. Or maybe it’s the way I was quiet, not wanting to butt into conversation topics I had no knowledge about. But that experience in Xianlin was not a pleasant one. My expectations for my year abroad versus the reality of the situation in front of me began catching up to me.</p>

<p>In the meantime, as Chinese classes really started rolling and oral presentations began being assigned, friend groups among foreigners started. In our small campus where I could walk from the back gate (where the canteen was) to the study room in my dorm building, there would hardly ever be a time where I wouldn’t stop for a conversation with someone I met along the way. Well, I was hardly ever by myself, since I ate lunch and dinner with the Italians, but it was an environment where most Westerners began to really know each other. A group of about thirty of us began having late night chats at a small drink store across our front gate deemed “老板’s” (laoban’s), and following that we had many a midnight adventure out on the town.</p>

<p>Throughout these social happenings, I began making some really good friends. I met a German girl that was half Chinese and half German raised in Germany, another American who lived in Maryland yet graduated from a university right near my house, and a lot of half-half mixed Europeans that had grown up with two cultures and languages. Now, all of these relationships were built off of conversations that happened in English. Back to the previously mentioned expectations versus reality, I had expected all relationships to be formed in Chinese; I was in China to improve my Chinese, after all. Yet, almost every friendship I formed was in my mother tongue. Even when my roommate and I had some pretty deep discussions, we were using English.</p>

<p>So my second month abroad wasn’t ideal. I dealt a lot with being separated– racially, culturally, and spiritually. I was a Chinese-American, born in China yet raised in the US. I couldn’t completely relate to any university-aged Chinese people I met, and they for sure didn’t express that they wanted to get to know me. On another level, I couldn’t completely relate to the Italians or any of the Europeans I began friendships with, because English was not their mother tongue and they could at least improve their language skills using English to communicate with other foreigners. And lastly, I felt torn apart by my goals. My mind, my spirit, told me I had come to China with a purpose– to learn Chinese, to make Chinese friends, and to learn more about myself. And that last point would be stretched out throughout the year abroad.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking back to October, I’d have to say my second month abroad included a whole lot of mixed feelings. Unfortunately, when we go abroad, we not only pack up our suitcases, memories, and belongings, but we also bring our expectations with us.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 2</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/15/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 2" /><published>2019-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/15/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/07/15/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I’ve returned home, life’s kept me moving. I came back to an untouched bedroom, an ever-busy and hectic schedule with my dad, a similar lifestyle at my mom’s, and the same high school friends doing the same exact things around town. However, over the last few days, I’ve felt like I need to recapture my experience abroad: to reflect, to think, and to improve from my experiences. So my first real blog post here is about my Month 1: September.</p>

<p>The first month really felt like a blur. There was, of course, an adjustment period: to the strange foreigners-living-abroad culture, my new Italian roommate, and living by myself for the first time ever. I needed to learn how to walk around my new campus at Nanjing Normal University without getting lost, where to get food, and how to  cope with only having myself as a reliable source of help. It was hard to eat dinner alone, to look on social media, and feel lonely while my friends from home had already settled into their college lifestyles.</p>

<p>Yet, I grew by myself. I realized a lot about home, both good and bad. I came to understand that high school was a bubble: nobody in the big picture cares about what you wear, where you live, or how many connections to school programs you have past those four years. Honestly, I’ve only kept a few strong relationships this past year from all people I spent four years with; mostly, I have memories. In the meantime, I began meeting other foreigners around campus and during touristy outings arranged in our group chat. Some were also on the same scholarship as I, others were friends with my roommate. An important person in my first month was another student on a gap year from a similar region as I in North Carolina (the Triangle); we were able to connect because of similar backgrounds and the same feeling of being lost. I also began forming a special relationship with my roommate that would be unparalleled with anyone else throughout the rest of the year.</p>

<p>As I made it through registration, venturing to the canteen without walking the opposite direction, and prepping for the placement exam in the school library, classes soon started. I began taking full immersion Chinese classes from 8 to 11:50 in the morning, with mostly Italians in my class that had come with my roommate from the same university in Italy. My classes felt strange: not because they were taught in a different language, but because there was hardly any REAL homework and the amount of effort I had to put in was significantly less than high school.</p>

<p>I soon got in a schedule, though, and I felt content. I knew the people in my class, I began friendships with other scholarship students, and my roommate and I ventured around the giant city taking the subway to shop, dine, or visit Nanjing landmarks. Life was good, life was settling.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since I’ve returned home, life’s kept me moving. I came back to an untouched bedroom, an ever-busy and hectic schedule with my dad, a similar lifestyle at my mom’s, and the same high school friends doing the same exact things around town. However, over the last few days, I’ve felt like I need to recapture my experience abroad: to reflect, to think, and to improve from my experiences. So my first real blog post here is about my Month 1: September.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 1</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/06/10/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2019, Blog Post 1" /><published>2019-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T21:01:47+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/06/10/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/06/10/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m sitting on a bench. Crying. Not because my legs are full of mosquito bites, not because I have to wait for my friend to finish her project and meet me, and not because I’m sweaty from hiking.</p>

<p>I’m sitting on a bench, crying, because I’ve realized how far I’ve come. After being abroad in Nanjing, China for ten months, I’ve gotten to meet up with one of my closest friends in high school. I was able to meet her other American classmates, talk to her roommate, and share my last year of experiences here in China.</p>

<p>And I’m not sad I’m leaving in a month. I’m ready to go home. Instead, I’m crying because of the growth I’ve experienced. I’ve come so far from being a seventeen year-old, ready to take on the world for a gap year before college. I’ve overcome so many obstacles, made crazy friendships, and learned incredible things about this world. All of these statements seem so broad, yet they’re all true. I’ve grown, and I’m proud of it.</p>

<p>So as I’m sitting on this bench, clicking through photos of friends from home, voice messaging friends back in Nanjing, and calling my mom, I’ve decided to start a blog. A blog chronicling the main difficulties I’ve experienced, the amazingness of studying abroad, and how much it means to be grounded, present- what it’s like to live in the moment, accept your surroundings, and grow.</p>

<p>Stay tuned, readers.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m sitting on a bench. Crying. Not because my legs are full of mosquito bites, not because I have to wait for my friend to finish her project and meet me, and not because I’m sweaty from hiking.]]></summary></entry></feed>