<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-07-09T17:28:04+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Violet Evans</title><entry><title type="html">Example post 3</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/02/23/example-post-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Example post 3" /><published>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-09T17:26:49+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/02/23/example-post-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/02/23/example-post-3.html"><![CDATA[<p>Content to be posted.</p>]]></content><author><name>violet-evans</name></author><category term="biology," /><category term="medicine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content to be posted.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/images/photo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/images/photo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blog Post 2</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2021/09/30/example-post-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog Post 2" /><published>2021-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-09T17:26:49+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2021/09/30/example-post-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2021/09/30/example-post-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>Content to be pasted.</p>]]></content><author><name>violet-evans</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content to be pasted.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blog</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/01/07/example-post-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog" /><published>2019-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-09T17:26:49+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/01/07/example-post-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/01/07/example-post-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>Why Data Analytics?…
Posted on November 7, 2023
During my first week in the program, the question I received the most was: “What made you want to come to the Institute?” Although my answer is complex, most often, I would respond that I studied biostatistics at UNC for my undergraduate studies – as if this was an explanation for pursuing graduate school. In this post, I reflect on my monumental experiences in undergrad by exploring my gradual realization of why I needed a master’s degree and discussing why I chose data analytics.</p>

<p>Reflection On Internship Experiences</p>

<p>Looking back at my three and a half years at UNC Chapel Hill, one of my proudest moments was when I received my dream summer internship at CVS Health. My main goal in professional extracurricular experiences was to gain real-world experience and get quality feedback on my work.</p>

<p>Intern in front of electronic poster display for Intern Summit for CVS.
I saw CVS Health as an opportunity to get hands-on experience on projects under direct supervision while working on a team to achieve larger corporate goals. The internship provided me with just those dreams – I worked on a health equity roadmap intervention for dialysis patients in Austin, Texas, collaborated with communication team members to update the internal Sharepoint site, and even shadowed a master’s data science student working on a similar project about social determinants of health. 
The jobs right out of undergrad fit for my skill set seemed to be focused on statistical programming rather than having a larger variety of tasks and independence in projects, while graduate school would provide education on a specialist topic and help me gain in-depth knowledge. I found a year-long remote research position at the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS) and decided that this experience would cement my decision for the future – if I enjoyed research, I’d pursue a PhD; otherwise, I decided I would do a master’s.</p>

<p>Intern in from of NIEHS sign
My summer, fall, and spring at NIEHS was a huge learning curve, but it provided time where I could experiment in R Studio, better understand bioinformatics, and explore a federal research environment. My program guided eleven undergraduates in professional workshops and through poster presentations to a broader NIEHS audience. I found value in the networking opportunities and the collaborative teamwork elements of the program. I also realized I enjoyed the coding and problem-solving more than the aspects of genomic data and methodology.</p>

<p>Reflection On Graduate School</p>

<p>I recognized the necessity of obtaining a master’s degree, yet the recurring question that plagued me was, “Which specific field should I pursue?” Some criteria that cycled through my mind included being relatively affordable, with a strong preference for in-state in North Carolina, having less than a two-year commitment, and providing a strong record for employment following graduation. I debated between a degree in public health, business, or statistics; specifically, UNC has a great two-year biostatistics master of science, and Boston University has a one-year applied biostatistics program with good ties to the life sciences.</p>

<p>Reflection On the Institute</p>

<p>The gradual realization of why I needed graduate school began to outweigh all of my criteria for staying in the public health realm of my undergraduate major, and I began to learn about the Institute for Advanced Analytics and NCSU. The 10-month program fulfilled all of my criteria for graduate school, and an added benefit was the close proximity to my family. I began leaning towards the idea of a non-public health data science program and committed to my decision. Since I’ve been in the program, I haven’t looked back, not even once. The “why data analytics?” question quickly became answered as coursework in foundational statistics, Python and R programming, and summer practicum ramped up. I found myself immersed in how to communicate data science to a non-technical audience and set personal goals for applying data analytics. The application aspect of the program has been crucial to my development as a data scientist.</p>

<p>In the last three months, I’ve already assembled a complete pie of knowledge and skills. Each slice on my plate represents a different aspect of our cohort’s learning journey, including statistics, programming, ethical considerations for data professionals, cross-cultural communication, computer security, networking in a professional context, and the art of setting tangible goals. We continue to fill our plates, one day at a time.</p>]]></content><author><name>violet-evans</name></author><category term="graduate school" /><category term="North Carolina" /><category term="Institute for Advanced Analytics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why Data Analytics?… Posted on November 7, 2023 During my first week in the program, the question I received the most was: “What made you want to come to the Institute?” Although my answer is complex, most often, I would respond that I studied biostatistics at UNC for my undergraduate studies – as if this was an explanation for pursuing graduate school. In this post, I reflect on my monumental experiences in undergrad by exploring my gradual realization of why I needed a master’s degree and discussing why I chose data analytics.]]></summary></entry></feed>