<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-21T00:59:31+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Violet Evans</title><entry><title type="html">A Day in the Life of an Onboarding Biostatistician</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/10/07/new-job.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Day in the Life of an Onboarding Biostatistician" /><published>2024-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/10/07/new-job</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/10/07/new-job.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I finally started my new role at the Durham VA Medical Center as a biostatistician. I have been looking forward to starting for so long! In my last blog post, I highlighted what the onboarding process was like; however, I left out most of the goal setting and career brainstorming I did over the last five months. I often find myself motivated by setting actionable goals by specific deadlines. It helps me brainstorm what I value and how I can achieve that end result in a sustainable, path-of-least-resistance way.</p>

<p>I’ve set the following three goals for the next few months at the VA, and went into my first day of work with these in mind:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Show up authentically to work. Make an effort to join conversations and provide input without being intimidated.</li>
  <li>Maintain work life balance. Be intentional in sustaining relationships (friends, family, etc.) without overextending.</li>
  <li>Become technically proficient and obtaining transferrable skills while at the VA. I want to feel like I don’t have to look things up a ton or struggle in coding.</li>
</ol>

<p>My mind full of goals, fears of traffic, and schedule jam packed, I showed up to work at 8 a.m. on my first day anxious but ready to start. I purposely left some time to figure out the parking situation; I wasn’t sure if I was going to be able to park in the parking deck that I scoped out the day before as there’s construction going on at the office. Parking is everyone’s first day nightmare, but especially mine as I hate driving! Thankfully, however, all the parking deck gates were open and I was able to smoothly snag a spot. I followed the trickle of people from the parking deck to the building, and quickly caught on that I walked into the basement. My manager, Sandra, and I had agreed on meeting on the concourse at 8 am sharp, so I rushed up the stairs in an effort to meet her. I stomped up to the ground floor stairwell to no avail- I couldn’t figure out how to get out! I also almost ran smack into two ladders sitting by the door. In a small panic, I heard a door behind me open. Taking a deep breath, I rushed over to the person emerging and blurted out, “Do you know how to get out?”. And alas, to my disbelief, I found Sandra.</p>

<p>My manager Sandra, my assigned onboarding buddy Livia, and I kicked off the morning by taking the elevator up to the sixth floor to the HR office. I found myself settling into the HR desk quickly while on the phone with a HR specialist, who was to help me obtain my temporary password to my login credentials. I hadn’t gotten a chance to grab my PIV card yet and could not log in to any of the things I needed to access on my computer! This call took longer than expected since the first phone call dropped. My morning was indeed off to a start.</p>

<p>However, things quickly took a turn for the better. After calling back (and going through the entire questionnaire again), I successfully received my temporary password. I also took some time to look over my HR welcome packet before my 6 hour onboarding call began. However, as 9:15 rolled around and I logged onto the WebEx, I realized that I had the time wrong. My new employee orientation was scheduled for 9:15 Central Time not Eastern Time!</p>

<p>I utilized my extra hour by spending time with Livia. She suggested that we take an extended tour around our office suite, which is located in the sixth and seventh floors of the iconic Mutual Life Towers, formerly known as the North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company Building. We also jump started the morning by grabbing coffee at Press Coffee &amp; Crepes, just a 10-minute walk away from the office. I enjoyed my morning dose of caffeine in the form of a cappuccino, and found Livia easy to converse with and get to know. The support I found from getting an assigned buddy was immense, because I knew that as I had questions arise, I’d have a go-to person.</p>

<p>After feeling rejuvenated and ready to tackle New Employee Orientation (NEO), I headed back for my 4-hour call. I’ll spare you all the details, but the rest of the NEO time block from 10:30 to 2:30 included PowerPoint informational sessions, a very comprehensive federal benefits overview, getting sworn into office, and running paperwork to one of our HR specialists, Nancy. I was eager to get some of the small paperwork items out of the way, like getting my working hours (called “tours of duty” in government lingo) filed and having computer access initiated.</p>

<p>To my surprise, I also got my seasonal flu shot on my first day of work. For a little backstory, the VA research group I joined is located at the Mutual Towers in downtown Durham, which is in a separate facility from the Durham VA Medical Center located off of Fulton Street. Although our HSR&amp;D group is housed under medical center, we get our own location, which in my opinion is great since parking is more ample. My first day coincided with a scheduled flu shot clinic where a nurse came over from the medical center to administer vaccinations; I was able to easily drop in to the pop-up-clinic during my lunch break. The great part about getting my shot at the pop-up clinic was that it saved me from filling out extra VA paperwork- if I had received my shot outside of a VA clinic, I’d be required under federal law to fill out additional paperwork to verify vaccination status. Once 2:30 rolled around, I exhaled a sigh of relief that I had gotten so much done in just a mere few hours at work.</p>

<p>After NEO, I retreated to my office on the seventh floor. I was pleasantly surprised to see a desktop set up at the desk, complete with a keyboard, wired mouse, and a set of brand new headphones waiting for me. I love that I got my own room with a door that closes! I quickly logged on with my temporary password to my login credentials and began setting up my accounts. By the end of the work day, I was able to access my VA emails, Microsoft 365, and even navigate the browser to see important websites. I felt so accomplished and excited to have conquered my first day at work. Being a biostatistician has been a dream of mine for so long, and</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="fulltime," /><category term="va," /><category term="biostats" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I finally started my new role at the Durham VA Medical Center as a biostatistician. I have been looking forward to starting for so long! In my last blog post, I highlighted what the onboarding process was like; however, I left out most of the goal setting and career brainstorming I did over the last five months. I often find myself motivated by setting actionable goals by specific deadlines. It helps me brainstorm what I value and how I can achieve that end result in a sustainable, path-of-least-resistance way.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A September Life Update</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/09/24/life-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A September Life Update" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/09/24/life-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/09/24/life-update.html"><![CDATA[<p>I will admit, it has been a while since I have updated my blog. However, it’s for good reason- I moved to Durham, began a part-time babysitting job, and also have been undergoing the paperwork process for the Veterans Affairs (VA) Medical Center. Since my full time role will be based in Durham and I am assigned to be full in-office for the first 90 days, I decided early on that it was important for me to move close to work. I am not a fan of driving, and in an ideal world, would like less than a 15 minute commute to work. Therefoe, I reached out to my former classmate at UNC that I stayed in touch with about living together. While she and I both studied biostatistics at UNC, I chose a more applied path at NCSU while she chose a more rigorous, math-heavy path at Duke. She’s currently a second-year master’s candidate at Duke’s M.S. in Biostatistics program. The timing was impeccable for a one year lease in Durham.</p>

<p>Our move went fairly smoothly, and I will spare you all of the details. However, I wanted to highlight the convenience of being able to get to most of my day-to-day places with ease. In our new apartment, I am able to get to Harris Teeter, Food Lion, the gas station, Five Below, and the auto shop within 3 minutes of driving. I am also a 8 minute drive from downtown Durham and hence my office in the N.C. Mutual Life building. I am really enjoying being close to all the places I need to be. I also enjoy being close to the families I babysit for!</p>

<p>I wanted to take the rest of this blog space to highlight the trials and tribulations I have been through for the VA Medical Center. Since receiving a verbal offer in May this year, I have had to jump through many hoops to complete paperwork. Although the team I am joining is a group local to Durham, I had to undergo the processing on a federal level. This meant after receiving my verbal offer, I had to wait for HR to reach out to me. My assigned HR specialist was “missing” for over two months during the summer, and paperwork did not start moving along until August. I received my intiial job offer paperwork in August, with multiple clearances to pass after signing.</p>

<p>The first task to complete was my forms and other tasks. This included my I-9, as well as other general onboarding paperwork in the USA Staffing onboarding account. Luckily, I was able to breeze through this stack of items fairly quickly in just a few hours.</p>

<p>The second task was to complete my background investigation and fingerprints through an electronic questionnaire (e-QIP). Since I have worked for the federal government before, I was thankfully auto-cleared through the e-QIP, saving me from multiple hours of paperwork. Thank goodness! For the fingerprints, someone from the PIV card office was assigned to me about scheduling federal fingerprints and creating a badge appointment. Once I was contacted, I was able to get into the office within a week or so. I really appreciated the location of my apartment since I could walk to the Veterans Affairs Medical Center and did not have to worry about parking! The fingerprinting, badging, and other forms only took about 30 minutes.</p>

<p>The last task I completed was working with Employee Occupation Health (EOH). The local EOH clinic contacted me to obtain a copy of my immunization record and draw blood. I was surprised that they did not need to take my vitals or do a physical health examination. The immunization records cleared immediately; however, drawing blood took some time. I had over seven vials of blood taken! This was to test for each of my immunizations, including MMR,  hepatitis, and COVID-19.</p>

<p>Now that my initial job offer paperwork is completed and all my clearances are checked off, I am waiting on my final job offer (FJO). Supposedly, my start date is either October 3rd or October 17th, due to the rotating two-week government pay periods. I have not yet received my FJO, but have reached out to both my manager and the assigned HR Specialist in the meantime. I received notice that the assigned FJO individual is again “missing”, so my next action item will be to track them down with hopes of starting on the 3rd. Stay tuned to hear about my start date and next adventures!</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="fulltime," /><category term="va," /><category term="biostats" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I will admit, it has been a while since I have updated my blog. However, it’s for good reason- I moved to Durham, began a part-time babysitting job, and also have been undergoing the paperwork process for the Veterans Affairs (VA) Medical Center. Since my full time role will be based in Durham and I am assigned to be full in-office for the first 90 days, I decided early on that it was important for me to move close to work. I am not a fan of driving, and in an ideal world, would like less than a 15 minute commute to work. Therefoe, I reached out to my former classmate at UNC that I stayed in touch with about living together. While she and I both studied biostatistics at UNC, I chose a more applied path at NCSU while she chose a more rigorous, math-heavy path at Duke. She’s currently a second-year master’s candidate at Duke’s M.S. in Biostatistics program. The timing was impeccable for a one year lease in Durham.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Reflection on Practicum</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Reflection on Practicum" /><published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2024/07/30/practicum.html"><![CDATA[<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>At the Institute, we all get assigned to practicum sponsors and teams of five for our yearlong project. Even though it was over 10 months ago, I still distinctly remember the nervous pit in my stomach when it was “reveal” day. With a class of 95 students and a split between Blue and Orange cohorts, I knew that I could end up with any four other classmates on my team. I also had no idea which government or corporate sponsor I’d be assigned to.</p>

<p>When reveal day came around, and as I tenderly opened the Google Sheets document revealing both sponsors and teammates simultaneously, I heaved out a sigh of relief. I got assigned to Andrew Burnette as team lead, who I knew to be level-headed, responsible, and kind. He and I were both in Blue cohort over the summer, and I had spoken to him a few times. I was unfamiliar with the other three names on the document- all three had been in Orange cohort over the summer and I had never spoken to them before. However, by graduation in May, our practicum team would be known as THE team; we all communicated well, produced incredible deliverables, and enjoyed each others’ company.</p>

<p>Tae Lee, my fellow Asian teammate, ended up being a close confidant throughout the job placement process. He and I did many mock interviews and prep together, and I always felt comfortable to talk with Tae whether it was about Asian cuisine, planning my solo trip to Korea, or asking about the D.C. food scene. Can you tell that I’m a foodie?</p>

<p>Blake Holmes, the class clown and lighthearted jokester, also became a great friend and helpful classmate. Since Blake and I often sat together in the front row, we often exchanged quips about our assignments. Never have I had a conversation with Blake and not felt immediately less stressed afterwards. Blake often helped lighten the mood of our team meetings with his seamless jokes.</p>

<p>I would say that my relationship with Salem Wear, the Alabama native and the only other girl on the team, had the most development. Initially, I expected us to automatically click and become close friends, especially since we were on the same homework team for the first fall module of the program. However, I experienced something like gradual friendship. As we continued through the fall semester and to the spring, I saw Salem to be responsible, kind, and conversational. One of her strengths throughout the job placement process was being able to empathize and remain positive. I also had the chance to partner with Salem on a practicum deliverable that focused on clustering. Through our working relationship, we became good friends and bonded over running.</p>

<p>Like all teams composed of diverse individuals, my team did have disagreements; however, one of our biggest strengths was communication. For example, if I had an idea that others disagreed about, I found that my teammates were willing to hear me through on my idea, make pro/con lists with me, and come to a team consensus on how to proceed. For example, I wanted our team to move over to Git for code changes and keeping consistency. I brought a PowerPoint deck to one of our meetings and suggested that we implement the strategy. Despite the difficulties in implementing the software on our remote servers, my team followed my PowerPoint instructions in getting Git set up. Once we completed the set up, various teammates voiced their concerns in a way that was both respectful but to the point. I appreciated the communication and willingness to give my idea a shot!</p>

<p>Reflecting on my time at the Institute, I feel that most of my challenges stemmed from the practicum project. Our team of five faced numerous obstacles and challenges in providing finalized deliverables to our sponsor. Despite this, I am incredibly grateful for my team’s support and flexibility. I hope to stay in touch!</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="teamwork," /><category term="ncsu," /><category term="practicum" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the Institute, we all get assigned to practicum sponsors and teams of five for our yearlong project. Even though it was over 10 months ago, I still distinctly remember the nervous pit in my stomach when it was “reveal” day. With a class of 95 students and a split between Blue and Orange cohorts, I knew that I could end up with any four other classmates on my team. I also had no idea which government or corporate sponsor I’d be assigned to.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/images/VEvans_Grad_20240418-38_Original.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/images/VEvans_Grad_20240418-38_Original.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Data Analytics?</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Data Analytics?" /><published>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2023/11/07/data-column.html"><![CDATA[<p>During my first week in the program, the question I received the most was: “What made you want to come to the Institute?” Although my answer is complex, most often, I would respond that I studied biostatistics at UNC for my undergraduate studies – as if this was an explanation for pursuing graduate school. In this post, I reflect on my monumental experiences in undergrad by exploring my gradual realization of why I needed a master’s degree and discussing why I chose data analytics.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On Internship Experiences</p>

<p>Looking back at my three and a half years at UNC Chapel Hill, one of my proudest moments was when I received my dream summer internship at CVS Health. My main goal in professional extracurricular experiences was to gain real-world experience and get quality feedback on my work.</p>

<p>I saw CVS Health as an opportunity to get hands-on experience on projects under direct supervision while working on a team to achieve larger corporate goals. The internship provided me with just those dreams – I worked on a health equity roadmap intervention for dialysis patients in Austin, Texas, collaborated with communication team members to update the internal Sharepoint site, and even shadowed a master’s data science student working on a similar project about social determinants of health. 
The jobs right out of undergrad fit for my skill set seemed to be focused on statistical programming rather than having a larger variety of tasks and independence in projects, while graduate school would provide education on a specialist topic and help me gain in-depth knowledge. I found a year-long remote research position at the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS) and decided that this experience would cement my decision for the future – if I enjoyed research, I’d pursue a PhD; otherwise, I decided I would do a master’s.</p>

<p>My summer, fall, and spring at NIEHS was a huge learning curve, but it provided time where I could experiment in R Studio, better understand bioinformatics, and explore a federal research environment. My program guided eleven undergraduates in professional workshops and through poster presentations to a broader NIEHS audience. I found value in the networking opportunities and the collaborative teamwork elements of the program. I also realized I enjoyed the coding and problem-solving more than the aspects of genomic data and methodology.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On Graduate School</p>

<p>I recognized the necessity of obtaining a master’s degree, yet the recurring question that plagued me was, “Which specific field should I pursue?” Some criteria that cycled through my mind included being relatively affordable, with a strong preference for in-state in North Carolina, having less than a two-year commitment, and providing a strong record for employment following graduation. I debated between a degree in public health, business, or statistics; specifically, UNC has a great two-year biostatistics master of science, and Boston University has a one-year applied biostatistics program with good ties to the life sciences.</p>

<!-- section break -->
<!--
  background: ;
  dark: ;
  size: ;
-->

<p>Reflection On the Institute</p>

<p>The gradual realization of why I needed graduate school began to outweigh all of my criteria for staying in the public health realm of my undergraduate major, and I began to learn about the Institute for Advanced Analytics and NCSU. The 10-month program fulfilled all of my criteria for graduate school, and an added benefit was the close proximity to my family. I began leaning towards the idea of a non-public health data science program and committed to my decision. Since I’ve been in the program, I haven’t looked back, not even once. The “why data analytics?” question quickly became answered as coursework in foundational statistics, Python and R programming, and summer practicum ramped up. I found myself immersed in how to communicate data science to a non-technical audience and set personal goals for applying data analytics. The application aspect of the program has been crucial to my development as a data scientist.</p>

<p>In the last three months, I’ve already assembled a complete pie of knowledge and skills. Each slice on my plate represents a different aspect of our cohort’s learning journey, including statistics, programming, ethical considerations for data professionals, cross-cultural communication, computer security, networking in a professional context, and the art of setting tangible goals. We continue to fill our plates, one day at a time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="graduate school" /><category term="NCSU" /><category term="Institute for Advanced Analytics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During my first week in the program, the question I received the most was: “What made you want to come to the Institute?” Although my answer is complex, most often, I would respond that I studied biostatistics at UNC for my undergraduate studies – as if this was an explanation for pursuing graduate school. In this post, I reflect on my monumental experiences in undergrad by exploring my gradual realization of why I needed a master’s degree and discussing why I chose data analytics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 10</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2021/11/15/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 10" /><published>2021-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2021/11/15/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2021/11/15/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>A Conclusion. (One Year Later)</p>

<p>As I kept a journal the whole time I was abroad, and re-read it all to figure out how to voice these blogs, I really want to share a meaningful entry. This was from 7/6, the night before I left Nanjing. The week before I wrote this, I had been running/biking/metro-taking around saying goodbyes, visiting tourist sites and celebrating my friendships with all the people that were also headed home.</p>

<p>“Ok now that it’s feeling like goodbye time, I just wanted to write this goodbye. Liike we moved all the furniture, it’s the first night I haven’t been busy, &amp; I’m just sitting here thinking about this semester. It hasn’t actually hit me I’m leaving, I’m saying goodbye to all that has happened here, all that’s changed me and all the relationships formed. Because last week felt like I was a happy robot, a person on a mission and a bubble of non-reality. But now it feels different, like tomorrow I finish packing up my adventure of a year, wrapping up my feelings, putting a bow on my head like a pacakge, &amp; traveling home. It’s like all my dreams are coming true, so it’s nostalgic but ITS FINALLY HAPPENING.</p>

<p>I have so many mixed feelings now that the day is actually here. I don’t know, I just feel like second semester went by so fast. I’m not sure where the time went, but it’s just been so good. I am going to look at old pics now to take a trip down memory lane….</p>

<p>As I’m continuing my night in my bed reading my Mao book, I am also thinking about how much culture I’ve learned. I think studying abroad &amp; explaining to other people why you think the way you think, why you do things the way you do also makes you grow. Just like saying, oh, in America, we do this. Or, oh, in this holiday, we do this. Like I literally explained to JiSoo that it was 4th of July a few days ago, and people wear swimsuits, grill out and put off fireworks. I don’t know, I also realize how much more chill am. Like I can just go with the flow and understand that other people also have plans. I’ve changed so much. I am so proud &lt;3.”</p>

<p>Something about my last weeks in China were so special. Perhaps it’s because I didn’t know how things would pan out, that I’d be meeting up with people on the fly. Or perhaps because I didn’t know time could even possibly feel so absolutely dragged out. It was as if every day was another closer to home, but also one less day with my friends. It was a strange time.</p>

<p>I think the most meaningful part of the end of my time in China was saying the goodbyes. Coming back to the US, I feel that my friends here just don’t share that same bond with me. The people in China were different, because they also experienced many struggles. Whether it was difficulties with the food, balancing schedules, or being in the same boat of homesickness, the people I met abroad were unique because of the obstacles we overcame together. These relationships made saying goodbye even better, and our last days together were even more valued. The best part of all the endings was that I had my friend Iana through every single goodbye meal with other people, up until the day I left. She was the one that said farewell to me, sending me off into the taxi towards the airport, and that meant a lot to me.</p>

<p>When I left, I was sad that all the relationships I made were put on pause, and that we had to part our ways. But I’m so glad I have made some forever friends. I know that if I ever backpack through Europe after college like I always talk about or if these friends come to the US, we will be able to reconnect, even without constant contact throughout the years. I shared a special bond with a lot of people, through hardships, laughter, and adventures. So this last post is dedicated to them– to the people that shaped my year abroad, that made learning Chinese more fun, and to the forever memories, ingrained into our hearts.</p>

<p>During the last few weeks, someone told me to end my blog with a picture of myself from the end of the year. So here I am. Trying to stay present. Open minded. Forever growing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gap" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Conclusion. (One Year Later)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 9</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2020/01/05/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 9" /><published>2020-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2020/01/05/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2020/01/05/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>“I feel like the past month has just been planning for the end, yet, it’s all the start for a new beginning.”- a quote by me from my journal.</p>

<p>By the beginning of June, I was ready to go home. I could count the weeks left on one hand, literally had every last weekend planned out, and knew how my final exams at the end of the month were going to pan out. Despite these hard facts and feelings that I had come so far, I didn’t actually know how my end time in China was going to turn out.</p>

<p>Turns out, June was one of the weirdest months of all. Living abroad, I fell into a pattern. Patterns of sleep, eating, studying, and going to class. But this last period of time felt like a deviation from those patterns. It was like the final home stretch, except 5 weeks long, 36 days on a countdown timer, and already full of lots of things planned out.</p>

<p>I had previously planned that I wanted to keep traveling on the weekends, and as mentioned before, I had a trip to see my friend from the US in Hangzhou scheduled. However, I had no idea that I was going to end up in the suburbs of Shanghai, visiting my former Chinese tutor on a whim. It was an absolutely wonderful visit, and it was so nice to feel like I was relaxing with a family. My tutor lives in a typical Chinese apartment, with three bedrooms, two bathrooms, and within walking distance to a supermarket. I loved staying with her, where I got to stay in my own room, play with her five year-old daughter, and get insight on how she,her husband and father all work together as a family. The Chinese family feels very close-knit and well-organized, and it was really a relief to have a pause from the campus lifestyle.</p>

<p>Upon return from Shanghai, I hit the home stretch of classes. The last two weeks felt so stretched out, but thank goodness I had a visit to Hangzhou planned among those weeks. Because it was Dragon Boat Festival, we had an extra day off from class! So again I hopped on a bullet train, slept the whole trip (I never have not slept on a train), and got off so excited to see my old friend! My friend, Holly, has been my friend since our freshman year of high school; we are really good friends and have been able to witness each other’s growth throughout high school. During my time in China, though, I hadn’t kept in touch with her; I think that was why she was able to see how much I had changed. (See the first post, my introduction!) It was really comforting to see a familiar face and spend time with another person of the same culture.</p>

<p>Talking with Holly’s roommate, meeting some of her other classmates, and adventuring with her study abroad group to a Dragon Boat Festival outing was so much fun. I think being able to express openly how I felt being away from home for almost ten months, and feeling completely at ease without having to think about cultural differences was freeing. That’s the moment I decided I wanted to start this blog, and then wrote and published my introduction.</p>

<p>And thinking back to that light bulb moment, I have absolutely no regrets. I am so glad I decided to write about this journey and all the hardships I encountered. Emotions in general are hard to express, and as a more logical person, it is even more challenging, but being able to channel my feelings into words has been a cathartic and productive experience.</p>

<p>The other part of my final weeks in China were also amazing, but I did feel like I had to have all my “lasts” and wrap up my semester. Finals were actually not as hard as midterms, and in between volunteering for the Nanjing Tech Expo Week, re-visiting all my favorite restaurants, and brainstorming where to visit after exams, I was so physically tired. I probably walked 20,000 steps a day for the last few weeks. Also, I think I had “my last bubble tea” 5 times for different flavors, so the calories burned evened out.</p>

<p>Another highlight of this last period of time in China was a visit from Holly and her roommate, plus the two other classmates I met in Hangzhou. The four of them took a train to Nanjing, and with me as their tour guide, we hit all my favorite tourist spots. The five of us visited the Sun-Yat Sen Mausoleum, JiMing Temple, the Nanjing City Wall, Xuanwu Lake, the famous Intercontinental building, and walked the streets around Suiyuan, my Nanjing Normal University Campus. Although I was completely wiped halfway through this one day expedition, it felt so cool to be a tour guide! It was like I was a local after living in Nanjing for ten months, and there were so many fun facts and memories I could share at each site. Having everyone down for such a big adventure and trusting me to guide them on the metro stops between each location was heartwarming. I had decided I wanted to end the evening before the Americans headed back with a group dinner with my Nanjing foreigner friends from school. My favorite restaurant, a 汤包 (soup dumpling) place was spacious enough for nine, so we all sat down to some delicious steamed delicacies. It was cool to see my worlds collide, as I knew how each person’s personality, and how the conversations from both my friend groups would unravel; it was also weird to hear that my school friends were telling Holly about how much I changed.</p>

<p>Lastly, my last week after exams in Nanjing is worth mentioning. I had decided back at the beginning of the school year there were certain landmarks I wanted to visit, so Iana and I agreed to keep each other accountable to the list. The very last day of exams, Iana, our German friend Josi, and I visited 夫子庙 (Confucious Temple), a region where little knicknacks are sold on old historic streets. My adventures with friends were non-stop from there– I had seven straight days of non-stop tourism. With so many different friends, a plethora of tears, and lots of farewell lunches, I had absolutely no time to sit around.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gapyear" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“I feel like the past month has just been planning for the end, yet, it’s all the start for a new beginning.”- a quote by me from my journal.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 9</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/29/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 9" /><published>2019-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/29/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/29/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>Looking back, April is tied with July as my happiest month abroad. SO much happened this month, and in the back of mind I knew I only had three more months left until it was time to go home. I suppose I mentally started wrapping up my year way too early, but with my friends in college finishing up and with warmer weather on the horizon, it felt like it was almost summer. But, I was still happy to be in school and learning a lot in classes.</p>

<p>As I settled into a routine of taking 2 morning classes for 三年级，汉语(reading&amp; writing) and 口语 (speaking), and also afternoon electives, I became better friends with my classmates. I ended up attending 3 out of the 4 electives offered, and because my classmates were required to take all of the classes, we were able to see each other every day in class. I really enjoyed the friend group of a few of my Korean and Thai classmates, along with my other two friends Matthew and WangFan. Matthew is from Malaysia/US/Mauritius, and WangFan is Chilean-Chinese. I think they are both around 8 years older than I; I know my Chilean friend is at least 26 or 27, but I really enjoyed their fresh perspectives and more sophisticated talks. Never will I forget our morning walks to the 包子 shop (although I ate breakfast before class, it was still a good excuse to stretch my legs) and laughing at their daily, never-changing orders.</p>

<p>All the people I saw in class and talked to during class break were all like older brothers just because they had so much more life experience. I liked feeling cared for, like a little sister with lots of big bros, and although we didn’t talk about our personal lives, we still had some very interesting conversations. Embedded in my memory is our group regularly sitting outside 八号楼(where our classroom was located) on class breaks, where we just chatted, drinking weird bottled teas from the shop across the street, and shared strange stories. During breaks, we mostly sat precariously on a thin, wiry fence, and I remember falling off of it once.</p>

<p>Outside of class, I had planned a day trip a week or so before I adventured to WuYuan county with Jisoo, my Korean roommate. We had booked train tickets and decided to go to Wuxi for a day. Wuxi is a city near Nanjing that’s also highly populated and plays a big part in China’s east coast economy; it is also full of many tourist locations and cultural heritage sites. We simply bought our train tickets and the night before, planned out what we wanted to see. That’s what I love about China: the convenience, ease, and the low stress of traveling. We decided on a visit to the LingShan Buddha, which was over an hour’s bus ride from the train station, and a trip to Tai Lake. Neither of these visits exactly panned out how we had planned, resulting in a several mile walk by a busy highway while observing the famous lake, being squeezed in the back of a bus without room even to scratch my nose (I really had to. But I couldn’t), and a bathroom pit stop at a random school. However, it was another really fun adventure and a good bonding moment with JiSoo, because she was so temperamentally different than my last roommate.</p>

<p>Another great part of April was the weather change. The winter had been so cold and suffocating, once warmer days came on the horizon, I could feel my spirit beginning to lift. I began to run outside on the track whenever I could. Those sunny days paired with birds chirping were absolutely perfect. Going to WuYuan, where the countryside was full of green grass and mud and streams, made me realize how much I missed nature. I even just sat in the overgrown grass in the middle of the track with my homework sometimes, just to feel the ants crawling on my leg or the itchiness of the grass. It reminded me of home, where I could go outside and see and touch the green grass if I wanted to at any time.</p>

<p>I definitely think April was my busiest month, because looking through my pictures, I also began biking with Iana during my free time, filmed a video interview project with my classmates, and celebrated a few friends’ birthdays. Plus, I still had weekly taekwondo, yoga, and language exchanges. Another trip with Mackenzie to some islands off of Shanghai also occurred in April, where we got to spend 12 hours on a local fisherman’s boat. Although we were only out of town for a few days, it was still so refreshing and full of adventure. Reading my journal describing this travel experience, I wrote “How was I awake at 5:30 hiking up a giant hill to get to an abandoned village, then laughing/ sprinting/ frantically hailing cars down through a tunnel to catch a boat, in Shanghai walking around the Bund, and now back laying in my bed, and it’s only 10 pm?”. Good memories. Good month.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gapyear" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking back, April is tied with July as my happiest month abroad. SO much happened this month, and in the back of mind I knew I only had three more months left until it was time to go home. I suppose I mentally started wrapping up my year way too early, but with my friends in college finishing up and with warmer weather on the horizon, it felt like it was almost summer. But, I was still happy to be in school and learning a lot in classes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 8</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/22/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 8" /><published>2019-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/22/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/12/22/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>After taking a four month pause from my blog to concentrate on my first semester of college, I’ve realized I need to finish recounting this journey. So much in China occurred that has shaped my life back in the US. I can’t even begin to explain the amount of influence this gap year has had on my mindset, on my interactions with other people, and the mentality that I can now take with me in my everyday activities. Reflecting on my school life at UNC, I’ve come to understand that I need to wrap this blog up for me, for closure.</p>

<p>Reading back over my March journal entries and revisiting the hoards of pictures taken has made me realize how much my second semester in China changed me. I think that this month was the start of a type of carefree freedom, an ability to drop all responsibilities and travel, to go explore, to go meet new people. I wanted to learn more about myself and see more new things.</p>

<p>March seems like light years away, something that happened in the past and shaped me, and feels so far off in the distance it’s almost intangible. So much occurred, from the start of a new semester to fresh social dynamics, it’s important to explain.</p>

<p>The beginning of the month was refreshing. Not only did I get a new roommate and had so much fun helping her around the city, from Walmart shopping adventures (free samples, anyone??) and showing her my favorite food spots, I also got to meet up with old friends. It was so fun to go back to school and actually have friends to text and meet up with. I reconnected with people over gifts and laughter and good food to share our holiday break’s stories; it was busy, but absolutely so full of happiness.</p>

<p>Something weird about March was the new social dynamic, because after the Italians from first semester left, there was a group of about 20 people from our old friend group staying. We all knew each other fairly well, but I think everyone began feeling like they needed their own space. This Westerner group was coined “The Survivors”, and our group chat became a place for random jokes and laughs, but actual tight-knit group dinners really died out.</p>

<p>As our first semester friend group became looser, I began exploring new friendships. I felt socially stretched, where I had my good friends Iana and Josi, and a few others I could comfortably talk to, but I also had my new Korean roommate, JiSoo. Having a Korean friend made a whole new realm of Asian friends open up at school. As the new semester began, I started going with Jisoo and her two friends to lunch. Although there were some Japanese and Korean students taking classes the first semester at NNU, I never really had the opportunity to interact with them. The new semester’s lunch allowed me to meet so many new people and use my Chinese more!</p>

<p>An important point about my old friends was that they really encouraged me to spend time with Jisoo. I was sad that I wouldn’t be able to see them as often, but I really did want to meet new people outside The Survivors group. I was thankful that my old friends wanted me to grow out of my comfort zone just as much as I did, and accepted me for who I was. I introduced my roommate to all my old friends at a birthday party, but the dynamic felt too foreign and uncomfortable for both of us. It was ok though, and I was more than glad to go with my new roommate to lunch and meet new people! Balancing school, old friends, and new friends was a real challenge, but I really loved my new adventures.</p>

<p>Another great part of the new semester was moving up to 三年级二班. My class was half full of Thai students, all from the same Thai university, and the other half of the class was just individual high-level students that were from various countries. I really enjoyed the harder content of my new classes and the fresh faces. Also, I began speaking to people in class only in Chinese, and I really enjoyed that I had a new group of people to converse with.</p>

<p>Other than the new social dynamics, I’d say that if I could highlight three great things of the new semester they would be:
1) Beginning visiting a fancy yoga studio with a free membership card my friend Matteo gave me
2) Joining taekwondo practice in Xianlin, the other NNU campus, more actively
3) Taking lots of food pictures</p>

<p>I guess I’ve always liked taking photos of things, because I remember religiously holding a mini Canon camera beginning in third grade on summer trips around China. In March, I really started taking LOADS of food pictures; I mean my camera roll was filled with pretty foods, strange foods, people with food, and any other situation food could possibly be in. My friends from home even started commenting when I sent them entire albums of not my adventures around Nanjing, but my food.</p>

<p>Lastly, one of the most memorable events of the month was a last minute backpacking trip to Wuyuan County, in Jiangxi Province. My American friend Mackenzie invited me for a weekend adventure backpacking around the county to see some of the famous seasonal 油菜花 (canola flowers). Although it was only a four day adventure, so much occurred; we hit up five different villages, had an adventure with our 缘分车, and missed our train on the way there (what a way to start out the weekend). If you want to hear about our stories of re-booking tickets, finding last minute places to stay the night of, and trying various 年糕 (sticky rice patties), ask me about it! Way too much happened in the span of this adventure to recount in this blog. Let me say, this adventure was surely a great way to wrap up the month.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gapyear" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After taking a four month pause from my blog to concentrate on my first semester of college, I’ve realized I need to finish recounting this journey. So much in China occurred that has shaped my life back in the US. I can’t even begin to explain the amount of influence this gap year has had on my mindset, on my interactions with other people, and the mentality that I can now take with me in my everyday activities. Reflecting on my school life at UNC, I’ve come to understand that I need to wrap this blog up for me, for closure.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 7</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/17/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 7" /><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/17/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/17/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>A Dedication to My Cat, Tootsie Roll</p>

<p>Change is real, and change is happening. Every single minute of the day, something on this planet changes. Whether it’s an event that resonates with us for every moment of our lives following it, or a minuscule change in another person’s life across the globe, it occurs. And it’s real.</p>

<p>Something I admit I have yet to embrace is change. My transition from a small, private middle school to high school was hard, and the transition from a North Carolina public high school, with 2,400 students in it, to my gap year in Nanjing was not easy either. So as move in day at my in-state, American university approaches, I feel hesitant to express my feelings.</p>

<p>February, my half-way mark of being abroad in China, really embodied these thoughts– change was in the winds, and I wasn’t sure how to feel about it. My month began with another trip to Guilin, Guangxi Province. I had been twice already that year, for both a holiday break in October, and in January with some friends, but I wanted to spend Chinese New Year (also known as the Spring Festival) with some family there. So, again, I hopped on a plane and traveled back to my birthplace.</p>

<p>During the eight or nine days of Spring Festival that I was there, I had the opportunity to meet lots of Guangxi Province locals that stopped in to pay a visit to my foster parents. I was staying with my foster parents and their daughter, so as tradition is pretty strictly still followed, almost all of their extended family members that lived fairly near came to 拜访 (visit and pay their respects). In summary, we ate so much delicious food, I had lots of people tell me their last memories of me as a baby, and then I fell really sick.</p>

<p>While my foster sister, her husband and I were in his old hometown in southern, rural  Guangxi Province, I started throwing up. I didn’t know why I was so sick; the only reason I could think of was that eating this delicacy that was a fried mix of sandworms with cashews made me sick. I think I also had a pretty high fever because I felt really light-headed and could hardly walk. The photo below is of the house where we stayed.</p>

<p>Upon return to Nanjing, I still didn’t really recover. I was staying at my mom’s house, about an hour from my campus, so I had all my meals provided for and didn’t have to worry about laundry (shout out to Mom, thanks!). However, I slept a lot and still continued having a lot of stomach problems. I did do a couple of things around the house, though. Below is a photo of me making 汤圆 (tāng yuán), a sticky rice dessert eaten for the Lantern Festival, which lands on the 15th day of the Spring festival; it marks the end of the holiday.</p>

<p>During this month of my holiday break, I also celebrated my 18th birthday. It was strange being away from my dad, my cats, my dog, and my friends, but I had my mom, so that was great! Here’s a picture of me and my cake.</p>

<p>Something that I experienced that was especially hard were changes back home in North Carolina. My beloved cat, Tootsie Roll, passed away at the old age of 13. My dad had gone to pet her and apparently she was cold. I felt such sadness and knew I had lost my life-long best friend when the news was broken to me, because through every stage of my life, my cat had been there for me. Well, cats can only be there so much for a human, but Tootsie was always lounging around looking for a pet, so if I ever needed an instant pillow, she was an easy first option. Tootsie also was always my warm blanket at night, my fluffy buddy, and my least favorite morning alarm. Being away from home for so long, already experiencing my family cat Tuffy’s death, and then changes in my dad’s life, my kitty cat’s death really was a wake-up call that change is inevitable. It’s always happening, it affects us all, and there’s nothing we can do to stop it.</p>

<p>So my month ended with lots of changes. Not actually a lot happened in Nanjing, because I wasn’t in school, but I found out three things: I caught a bacterial intestinal infection, I began feeling very old after becoming ‘legal’, and things at home in the US were changing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gapyear" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Dedication to My Cat, Tootsie Roll]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 6</title><link href="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/07/china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nanjing 2018-2019, Blog Post 6" /><published>2019-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:58:23+00:00</updated><id>https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/07/china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://venorthcarolina.github.io/violets-website/2019/08/07/china.html"><![CDATA[<p>January was a really, really good month and every one of my days, for the most part, were different.</p>

<p>Beginning with my week one, I began wrapping up my holiday feelings. No more festivities past our New Year’s Eve party, no more group dinners, and no more free time with friends. Well, I did go to a big dinner the night before a final exam, but that was an exception– we went to get the famous Beijing roast duck! The first week, I had to begin studying for my four classes of Chinese. Two classes were main “core” class, Chinese reading/writing and a listening/speaking class; the other two were for essay writing and composition and business Chinese.</p>

<p>I really felt confused studying for exams during the second week: not because I did not understand the content, but because I wasn’t quite sure what I was studying for. My grades did not transfer back to college in the US, and I never had planned to study anything Chinese related in college. My motivation definitely lacked during this week, but I crammed all the content in and finished with all A’s for the semester.</p>

<p>The third and fourth week of January were some of the best weeks I experienced in China. My friends and I had planned a big trip to Guilin, Guangxi for sightseeing around the city and visiting the nearby rice terraces after exams finished. Guilin happens to be my hometown and birthplace, so although I did hesitate at first about joining, but once I made my decision to tag along, I was exuberated! We took an 8-hour train ride down to Guilin, stayed in an amazing hostel, explored the city (with me as everyone’s guide, of course), and tried some yummy foods.</p>

<p>As wonderful as the week was, traveling with seven other people can be very exhausting. Some of my best friends, the Italians, were not returning the following semester, so I said my tearful goodbyes and wished them good luck, then flew back to Nanjing. I only had a couple days back in Nanjing before my family and I vacationed in Thailand for a week, so I settled in at my mom’s and focused on packing.</p>

<p>Switching from traveling with seven other young people, down to do anything and visit everything, to traveling with a four year old (my sister) was quite a transition. My mom, stepdad, sister and I spent a whole week in Bangkok, and our time there was very slow and relaxing. All the Thai food we tried, from nice and air-conditioned restaurants to aromatic street food, blew my mind. Also, the famous landmarks were amazing to sightsee and easy to get to, all with a venture on the SkyTrain and boat ride down the Chao Phraya River. Pictured below are some of my favorite sights, foods, and things we did.</p>

<p>I wrapped up my contrasting month with a big change– I cut off 8 inches of my hair! Before leaving the US, I planned that I would cut off as much hair as possible to donate to non-profit hair donation center. However, my hair grew really long over the first semester, almost hitting my elbow, and I could not stand it any longer. I got a salon recommendation from my Chinese friend, booked an appointment online, and headed over for the big chop with my friend Emily. The hairdresser almost cut off the eight inches without the hair being tied in the ponytail, which would’ve been tragic, but Emily caught his mistake, and I walked out of the salon with eight less inches of hair on my head. The haircut symbolized a new start, a fresh look, and a willingness to make the rest of my year as good as the last few weeks.</p>]]></content><author><name>Violet Evans</name></author><category term="nanjing," /><category term="china," /><category term="gapyear" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[January was a really, really good month and every one of my days, for the most part, were different.]]></summary></entry></feed>